DELICIOUS IN DUNGEON
《迷宫饭》
Laios and his crew agreed to head back to the surface.
莱欧斯等人决定回到地表
I don't want to lose you guys!
我不想失去你们这些队友啊！
You guys…
各位…
The strength of their bonds was reaffirmed.
他们确认彼此间的情谊 变得更加稳固
A little earlier…
将时间倒回稍早之前…
Are you awake now?
你的意识清楚吗？
Do you feel any discomfort?
身体没有异状吧？
You seem well enough.
看来没什么大问题
You were low on blood, so I used some goat blood.
因为血量不够 所以我用了羊血应急
But it's not ideal.
但无法完美替代
You should head back to town.
最好先回城镇一趟
If you had stayed dead on the water, you'd be fish bait by now.
要是死在水中 现在早已成为鱼群的饲料了
You should thank whoever pulled you out.
好好感谢拖你们上岸的人吧
Do you think it was…
拖我们上岸的人该不会是…
Kuro!
小黑！
I recognize these scents.
我闻过这味道
An elf, a tall-man, a half-foot, and a dwarf.
精灵、长身人、半身人、矮人
The same folks who took our treasure.
是偷走宝物的那群人
I suspected it was them!
果然是那些家伙！
I require a revival fee.
我要收复活费
I'll only charge you for the goat.
只需付山羊的钱就好
Right, I remember now.
对了 我想起来了
We were attacked by Fish-men and…
我们被鱼人袭击…
So, we died again.
然后又死了
This will do.
金额确认没错
Are they adventurers?
是冒险者？
Are you…
你是…
What?
怎么了？
Nothing.
没事
Let's go, Namari.
走吧 娜玛莉
Yeah, coming.
好 来了
You're even making eyes at a dwarf?
你也将矮人算在恋爱对象内了？
You have no standards.
真没节操
Well, I've never picked my friends based on how tall they are.
毕竟我从不会用身高 来挑选要来往的同伴
Is that so?
是喔
Our provisions are gone!
食物不见了！
They must've stolen from us again!
肯定又是被那些家伙偷走了！
Food.
我们的饭
How dare they!
开什么玩笑？
Not again.
又来了
They've taken our food but left our money?
他们不偷财物 只偷食物？
Maybe they've depleted their own supplies.
可能是他们的食物刚好见底
Infuriating.
令人气愤
We need to take them to task.
我绝对要好好教训他们
What do we do, Kabru?
要怎么办？喀布尔
We've got no other option.
也别无选择
Let's head back to town.
我们回镇上吧
What? Seriously?
什么？你是认真的吗？
Without catching the thieves?
不去抓犯人？
We're out of provisions, so we can't push on.
但既然我们没有食物 也无法继续前进啊
Let's admit our own lack of skills.
就承认我们是实力不足吧
Just like those people said,
正如那群人所说的
we should be thankful we're still breathing.
光是这条命还在 就该心存感激
If that's your call, Kabru, I'm with you.
既然这是喀布尔的决定 我会听你的
Same here.
我也是
If you promise you won't forget about finding those thieves,
只要你答应不会放弃寻找犯人
I'll follow your lead.
那我也同意
You have my word, Rin.
我向你保证 铃
Kuro will follow Mickbell.
小黑会听米克贝尔的话
We're going to be deep in the red after this expedition.
这次的探索让我们赔大了
It's getting foggy.
起雾了
Everyone, watch out--
大伙 要留意…
This isn't a natural fog.
这并非自然形成的雾
Could a monster be causing this?
是魔物搞的鬼吗？
A Fish-man?
鱼人？
Where did they come from?
怎么突然冒出这么多？
Dammit. I'll have to fight.
可恶 只能应战了
Here it comes!
要来了！
The way it wields its axe like it's mowing something down…
这种将斧头猛力横扫的攻击方式…
I know it very well.
我对敌人的挥砍方式很熟悉
Yes.
对了
It's…
这是…
Shh!
嘘！
It's okay. Calm down.
没事的 冷静一点
Daya, it's me.
戴阿 是我
This fog is illusion magic.
这阵雾是幻术魔法
The confused one with the drawn weapon has to be Kuro.
那个拔出武器 不知所措的是小黑
And the one standing in a daze is Holm.
在发呆的那个是霍尔姆吧
He tends to freeze when too much happens all at once.
他有个习惯就是 同时发生太多事就会僵住
And the one who bolted earlier must be Mick.
然后刚刚逃走的应该是米克
In that case, the biggest threat here is…
如此一来 现在最危险的对象是…
Rin.
铃
Just as I feared, she's chanting something.
果不其然 她正在咏唱
She has the power to reduce us all to cinders.
她能够让在场的人全都化为灰烬
The only way to peacefully interrupt a mage's incantation is…
能和平中断魔术师咏唱的方法是…
Rinsha.
铃夏
Do you see? This is an illusion.
你这下懂了吧？这是幻术
It's a shame she's in the form of a monster.
可惜在我眼中你是魔物的样子
Now then, how do we dispel this illusionary fog?
接下来 该怎么驱散这阵幻术迷雾？
It's not this one.
不是这家伙
A spellcaster wouldn't come charging with a weapon.
施术者不会手持武器进攻
They'd observe from a distance.
而是会保持距离观察我们
That one!
是那家伙！
What?
什么？
You got us.
我们认输
We surrender.
要投降
Let him go, will you?
可以请你放过他吗？
These guys…
这群人…
They are the corpse retrievers we ran into on the upper floor!
是我们在上面遇到的尸体回收商！
This isn't a chance reunion, is it?
看来这场重逢并非偶然
You were following us, right?
你们跟踪了我们吧？
What do you mean?
什么意思？
Retrieving bodies in the lower levels pays better,
回收越深层的尸体 报酬便越高
thanks to Island subsidies.
因为岛上会发补助金
We were intent on getting our stolen loot back
我们激动地想取回失窃的战利品
and entered a level we weren't ready for.
踏入自身实力不足应付的层数
All they had to do was leisurely follow our trail
他们只要悠哉地跟在我们后面
for more lucrative corpses.
就能轻松捡到更有赚头的尸体
Oh.
这样啊
Infuriating.
真不爽
But you guys were a little too slow.
但你们稍微来迟了
By the time you found us, we were already resurrected
当你们找到人时 我们已经在其他人的帮助下复活了
and on our way back to the surface.
并准备回到地表
You got antsy and resorted to extreme measures.
你们在情急之下使出强硬手段
You used magic to make us turn on each other.
用幻术魔法让我们自相残杀
Close, but not quite.
不完全正确
Actually, it would've been ideal if you caught up with your thieves
其实对我们而言 你们追上窃盗犯
and fought with them and killed each other.
接着互相残杀才是最好的结果
But what a letdown.
实在是可惜
We didn't think you'd get taken out by monsters so quickly.
想不到你们这么快就被魔物杀死了
You…!
你这混蛋…
Stealing from and attacking fellow adventurers is a serious offense.
冒险者间的窃盗与战斗行为属于重罪
I'll be reporting this to the Lord of the Island.
我们会向岛主报告
How about we make a deal?
要不要来场交易？
Going back empty-handed would be a loss for you.
就这样空手而归 对你们而言也只有损失吧？
Two of our comrades are lying dead over there.
正好我们有两名队友倒在那边
Take them to the resurrection office.
把他们带去复活处吧
You should be able to make a tidy sum.
这样你们应该能赚到不少钱
They're only unconscious.
他们只是昏过去而已
I'll testify that they were attacked by Fish-men.
我会作证 说他们惨遭鱼人杀害
Our share would be…
然后我们就分…
Let's see, 40…
我想想 四成…
No, 30% will do.
不 三成就好
What do you say?
意下如何？
It's not a bad deal for you.
你们丝毫不会吃亏喔
Fine. Deal.
好吧 成交
Kabru…
喀布尔…
You bastard!
你这混蛋！
I'm not surprised.
我就知道事情会变成这样
That's our Kabru!
那样做才对嘛！
Humans really are easy to kill.
果然还是对付人类比较轻松
Tall-man, dwarf, gnome, they all share the same weak points.
不论是长身人、矮人 还是地精 要害部位都相同
Even their movements are similar.
身体的活动方式也相同
If only monsters were the same, it'd make things simpler.
如果魔物也都一样就好办多了
Kuro, could you go find Mick?
小黑 能麻烦你把米克找回来吗？
Woof!
汪！
Kabru.
喀布尔
What do we do with him?
要怎么处置他？
P-Please let me go.
请饶过我
I didn't know anything!
我毫不知情！
You don't care about breaking the curse on the dungeon
不仅无心解除迷宫的诅咒
or exterminating monsters.
也无意将魔物赶尽杀绝
More and more people are making a quick buck by robbing others.
借抢夺他人财物 每天赖以维生的家伙日渐增加
At this rate, decent people will leave the Island.
再这样下去 正派之人会纷纷离开这座岛
That's why I can't forgive people like you.
所以我不会放过像你们这样的家伙
Please don't.
求你住手
Kabru.
喀布尔
Sorry about what I did earlier.
关于刚刚的举动 我很抱歉
It was the only thing I could think of.
我在情急之下只想到能那样做
What are you talking about?
你是指哪件事？
I don't know and I don't care to know.
我既没印象 也没兴趣知道
That's a relief.
那就好
I'm growing impatient, and we're not making much progress.
我光顾着焦急 却完全没有前进
You're right.
是啊
And this is where our impatience led us.
而焦急的下场就是这样
It sucks.
真的糟透了
Can't you offer some encouragement once in a while?
你偶尔也鼓励我一下嘛
There's no use sugarcoating it.
自欺欺人又没意义
This is the reality of our abilities.
这就是我们目前的实力
The Lord of the Island only sees the dungeon as a profitable pit.
岛主只将迷宫视为值钱的洞穴
Even if it runs out of treasure,
就算将财宝拿尽
he believes he can get by on monster hides and bones.
也觉得能继续 用魔物的皮与骨头勉强糊口
But the truth is, no one will enter the dungeon once it's fully explored.
但实际上没人会特地去 彻底探索完毕的迷宫
Either because there's no fortune to be made
可能是少了一夜致富的梦想
or because it doesn't excite the adventurous spirit.
或是无法挑起冒险精神
Fewer and fewer people will be here.
潜入迷宫的人日渐减少
Monsters will spill out from the dungeon and attack citizens.
接着魔物自迷宫内涌出 居民因此饱受折磨
That's how many settlements have fallen into ruin.
许多聚落因此成为废墟
We must lift the curse on the dungeon quickly.
我们得赶紧解除迷宫的诅咒
There's no room for monsters or dungeons in this world.
这世上不需要魔物与迷宫
Yeah.
好
I'm hungry.
我饿了
Being resurrected makes you hungry, doesn't it?
复活后肚子都会饿呢
Kabru!
喀布尔
Those guys had quite a bit of valuables on them!
他们身上有不少值钱的东西喔！
All right.
好
Take their food, but toss the rest into the lake.
只拿走食物 其他的就扔进水里吧
What? Are you serious?
什么？扔进水里？
If we took their valuables, we'd be no better than them.
要是拿走那些 我们跟他们就是一丘之貉了
Once that's done, let's have a light meal.
处理好后 就稍微吃点东西吧
-Sounds good.
-赞成
ADVENTURERS' RATIONS SALTED MEAT
（冒险者随身粮食组 盐腌肉）
BREAD, WINE, NUTS AND DRIED FRUITS
（葡萄酒 面包 果实与水果干）
-Let's dig in!
-开动了！
Yum!
好吃！
They're eating pretty well.
他们吃的食物还真优质
Corpse retrievers make a pretty penny, huh?
当尸体回收商很赚钱啊？
Especially if they're the ones creating the corpses and bringing them back.
而且他们还自行制造尸体 将其带回去呢
But won't the Lord of the Island catch on?
岛主都不会察觉到吗？
There's a screening process to claim rewards from the Island.
这座岛发放的报酬会经过审查
They must've been pretty clever to slip through that.
看来他们巧妙地蒙混过去了
Or maybe they're in cahoots with more parties than we realize.
或是愿意协助的其他队伍意外地多
That's so rotten.
人品败坏
In the end, they're just digging their own grave.
明明只会自掘坟墓
Will you inform the Lord of the Island?
我们要跟岛主报告吗？
I doubt that Lord will come up with a good solution.
我不认为那位岛主会有好方法解决
Newbies like Doni will end up getting the short end of the stick.
到头来只有多尼那些新手会吃亏
If only that stupid Lord gains so much weight that he pops.
真希望那个蠢岛主 继续增肥 然后自爆
Then the elves will come swooping in.
那样的话 精灵就会急忙赶来了
We still need him to hold out as a bulwark.
现在还是得靠他充当堤防撑下去
Anyway, a tall-man, a dwarf, a half-foot, and an elf, huh?
不过他们是长身人、矮人 加上半身人和精灵？
What's this about?
你在说什么？
The party that cast a ghost-warding spell on us.
对我们施展驱灵术的队伍成员
You mean those treasure thieves.
你是指那群宝石小偷啊
Food robbers.
食物小偷
There aren't many parties with an elf.
有精灵的队伍很稀奇
We could identify them with some narrowing down.
只要筛选一下 应该就能找到
Do you think it's Doni and Fionil?
该不会是多尼和菲奥妮露吧？
It's hard to imagine them venturing down to the third floor.
我不认为多尼他们会来地下三层
And I find it odd that they're only a party of four.
他们是四人组这点也让我很在意
It's rather reckless of them.
他们探索得太鲁莽了
Rin, Holm.
铃、霍尔姆
Do you notice anything about this ghost-warding spell?
对于这个驱灵术 你们注意到什么了吗？
You still have it on?
你还戴着那东西？
I mean, it's evidence.
毕竟算是证据嘛
I'm not familiar with spells like that.
我对那类法术不太熟
Let me take a look.
让我看看
It screams "honor student."
给人的感觉就是“模范生”
It looks like it's straight out of a textbook.
做法宛如课本上的内容
And whoever did it wasn't used to it.
而且对方大概对此不太熟练
They might even be a magic school graduate.
或许是魔法学校毕业的
All graduates produce similar spells.
毕竟那边的学生咒语写法都大同小异
And there's no doubt it's the work of an elf.
反正肯定是精灵写的
Magic school…
魔法学校…
Hmm, magic school, huh?
是喔 魔法学校啊？
Interesting.
原来如此
What? What is it?
什么？怎么了？
Well, I have a hunch about whose party this might be.
没有啦 我好像有点头绪
It's just a guess, but
虽然只是猜测 不过呢
I'd be thrilled if I'm right.
猜对的话可真令人开心
Out with it. Cut the drama.
什么啦？别卖关子了
Well,
那个…
I think it's the party with the Touden siblings.
大概是托登兄妹的队伍
Touden? You mean those two?
托登？是指那两人？
They don't strike me as the criminal type.
他们感觉不像会和犯罪扯上关系的人
What's your reasoning?
你的根据是？
First, if I remember correctly, the sister is a magic school graduate.
首先 我记得托登兄妹中的妹妹 是魔法学校的毕业生
But the one who cast the ghost-warding spell was an elf.
但施展驱灵术的是精灵吧
And those siblings are tall-men.
那对兄妹是长身人耶
Hold on, let me finish.
等等 先听我讲完
The elf in their party seemed pretty close to the sister,
那队伍里的精灵 看起来跟妹妹的感情很要好
as if they were childhood friends.
好到宛如从小就认识
So I figured they must've attended the same magic school.
所以我就猜她们可能 是毕业于同一间魔法学校
Magic school graduates are rare around here,
魔法学校的毕业生在这很稀少
especially if they're an elf.
更别说是精灵了
I suppose it's possible.
并非不可能
But it's not enough to go on.
但光凭这点并不充分
Plus, Kuro only smelled one tall-man.
更何况 只有一位长身人的味道吧？
If they're siblings, he should've smelled two.
兄妹的话应该会有两位
Are you suggesting that's why they're venturing with a small group?
该不会这就是 少人数硬闯迷宫的理由？
Exactly! One of the siblings got lost,
没错 兄妹其中一方惨遭不测
and there was a disagreement in the party about whether to rescue them.
于是就要不要救人和同伴发生争执
I think so because we just crossed paths with a former member of their group.
我会这样想 是因为刚刚 有和其中一位队员擦身而过
They had disputes over their goals and income even before this.
他们过去曾因目标与收入争吵
And maybe this incident led some of them to leave.
可能是这件事导致数人离队
Now desperate, they're resorting to stealing treasure and food.
接着由于贫困 对宝石与食物下手
-You're starting to convince me. -Right?
-好像有点说服力了 -对吧？
But Kuro, you mentioned catching a whiff of a dwarf too.
但小黑说闻到了矮人的味道
I did. Strong dwarf scent.
闻到了 而且非常浓
That's odd then.
这样的话很怪吧？
Why would they still have a dwarf with them?
怎么还有矮人在队伍里？
Maybe they recruited another one.
或许是新雇用的
Who else is in their party?
那队伍里还有哪些人？
Let's see.
我想想
The tall-men are Laios, Falin,
长身人有莱欧斯和法琳
and probably Shuro, an Easterner.
还有或许是东方人的修洛
There's Namari, the dwarf we saw earlier,
刚才遇到的矮人娜玛莉
and Marcille the elf.
加上精灵玛露希尔
I think the half-foot's name was Chilchuck or something.
半身人好像叫奇尔查克
Assuming this is the Touden siblings' party,
如果是托登兄妹的队伍
one of their siblings, as well as Shuro and Namari, departed.
那就是兄妹之一与修洛、娜玛莉离队
And another dwarf joined them, I think.
再加入一位新的矮人
I see. So the woman back there was Namari.
这样啊 原来刚刚那女的就是娜玛莉
Do you know anything about her, Daya?
你知道些什么吗？戴阿
Only her name.
听过这名字
She's pretty well-known.
因为很出名
She's the only daughter of a guy known as the "Arms Dealer."
她是人称“武器商”之男的独生女
"Arms Dealer"?
“武器商”？
He used to control the arms trade on this Island.
过去掌管岛上武器流通的男子
But one day, he was found embezzling a hefty sum and vanished.
但某天被发现贪污巨款后失踪
They say he's one of the reasons
据说就是这件事
the Lord of the Island has a negative view of dwarves now.
导致岛主对矮人印象很差
A lot of dwarves suffered because of him.
让许多矮人因此吃尽苦头
Including me.
包含我在内
No honorable dwarf would want to follow in his footsteps.
正常的矮人应该不会接替她的位置
So maybe she's not an honorable dwarf.
或许就是不正常的矮人吧
The scent I caught was intense.
实际上那味道闻起来很不妙
I know something about this Chilchuck guy.
那个奇尔查克我也知道一点
He's a middle-aged fellow,
明明是老大不小的大叔
but he acts like he's the representative for all the half-foots on this Island.
却一副代表岛上半身人的态度
He's a greedy guy who insists on making contracts through the guild
说什么“想跟人签约时 就得经由公会”
and paying broker fees.
然后收取中介费 是个贪财的家伙
I want no part of that, so I'm steering clear.
我不想加入 所以逃了
I mean, if he found out I hired a Kobold, I'd get an earful for sure.
因为要是被发现我雇用狗头人 绝对会被说闲话
You wouldn't want that, right?
你也不希望这样对吧？
You want me to keep hiring you, don't you?
小黑想被我雇用对吧？
Mick gives me food.
米克会给我饭吃
Mick is a good boss.
是个好雇主
I bet he's working him hard for measly wages.
一定只付低薪压榨他吧
Holm, you shouldn't make assumptions like that.
霍尔姆 不能仅凭猜测就说那种话
Anyway, Rin, the Eastern tall-man is from your neck of the woods.
然后那个东方来的长身人 是铃的同乡对吧？
Maybe you know each other.
该不会认识吧？
Oh, please.
我说你啊
Don't group us together just because we're both Easterners.
不要随便把东方人直接概括在一起
Depending on the region, we don't even speak the same language.
有些地区甚至连语言都不相通
And Shuro isn't a name from my island.
我的岛上不会取修洛这种名字
I might have more information on him then.
那我可能比较了解
He was a bit of a loner even in Touden's crew.
他在那队伍里也有些格格不入
He came to the Island with a few other Easterners,
他是跟几位同乡一同来到岛上
then joined Touden's party alone.
独自加入托登兄妹的队伍
He gave off this vibe that he wasn't your average person,
散发出绝非常人的气场
and it seemed like he was venturing into the dungeon to test his skills.
挑战迷宫也只是想试试自己的本领
But he left the party, huh?
他离队了啊？
He didn't strike me as someone concerned about rewards or dangers.
感觉不像是会在意报酬与风险的人
Could it be that both siblings left, and he's still in the party?
该不会是兄妹俩都不在了 只剩他在队伍里？
Nah, that's unlikely.
这也不太可能
Kabru, you remember details about people to the point where it's creepy.
喀布尔对其他人的事情 记性好到令人毛骨悚然
Why do you sound so excited?
为何你看起来这么开心？
Because it's fun. It's really exciting!
当然开心啊 非常开心！
There are countless people on this Island, each with their own motives.
有许多人在这岛上 都抱着不同的想法在行动
But when their entirely different actions intersect,
但当这些零散的行动紧扣在一起时
it sparks a historic event involving a whole lot of people.
就会引起将许多人 卷入其中的历史性事件
I thought this was just a boring case of theft,
本以为是无趣的窃盗事件
but I sense something interesting is about to happen.
但我现在有种预感 即将发生很有趣的事
I hope this crew is the Touden siblings' party.
真希望就是托登兄妹的队伍
Because for a long time now,
因为我打从很久以前
I've been itching to see their true colors revealed.
就在等待他们的假面具 被撕下的那一刻
Do you have a grudge against them or something?
你跟他们有仇吗？
It's not like they've wronged me.
我没有被怎么样
In the past, Laios apparently made a fortune in a gold-peeling crew.
他们过去曾加入剥金团赚了不少钱
But he was sharing most of his earnings
但是这些收入
with comrades who couldn't enter the dungeon due to illness or injury.
几乎全给了因生病或受伤 无法潜入迷宫的伙伴
That's noble of him.
是桩美谈嘛
Yes, it's a touching story.
对 的确是桩美谈
But there's more to it.
但这故事还有后续
His comrades had long recovered, but kept taking the money.
他们明明都痊愈了 还是继续收钱
In the end, they never returned to adventuring
到头来 他们没回去当冒险者
and now peddle smuggled goods on the Island.
现在在岛上贩售违禁品
"I shall bestow everything to whoever defeats the lord of the dungeon."
“我将赐予击败迷宫之主之人 我国拥有的一切”
That's what some king-like figure of this country supposedly said.
据说是国王的男人曾留下这句话
Regardless of whether you could truly obtain everything or not,
先不论是否真能得到他所拥有的一切
this dungeon itself is a legacy left by ancient elves.
这迷宫本身就是古代精灵留下的遗物
I'm sure it holds significant power.
肯定有相当大的影响力
That's why I don't think it should fall into the hands of those siblings.
所以我认为得到这一切的人 不该是那对兄妹
They're not saints.
他们并非善人
They're just indifferent to people.
纯粹是对人类没兴趣
Just like the Lord of the Island.
就跟那位岛主一样
We know, Kabru.
我们都懂 喀布尔
We believe you're the only one.
我们都认为非你莫属
The only one to drive out that stupid Lord as well.
包含赶走那位蠢岛主在内
But if you're still struggling with monsters in this area,
但光对付这区的魔物就如此吃力
you've got a long road ahead of you.
还有好长一段路得走呢
You're right.
你说得对
Well then, shall we get going soon?
那么差不多该出发了
May we make it back without any issues.
希望能平安无事地回去
Whoa! That was close!
天啊！好险！
Blade Fish!
是刃鱼！
Don't let them distract you!
别被鱼夺走注意力！
Watch your step!
大家要小心脚下…
A Kraken? No, it's a Sea Serpent!
克拉肯？不对 是大海蛇！
Rin! Get back!
铃！快退开！
Incant--
咏唱…
Holm!
霍尔姆！
I can't summon her in this situation!
这状况没办法叫她出来！
There's no telling what might get mixed in!
会混入奇怪的东西！
Don't panic.
别慌张
It's up to you to do something, Kabru.
喀布尔 你得想办法解决才行
It's not a creature that makes complicated movements.
它并非行动复杂的生物
Observe its motions, and aim for its carotid artery.
看清对方的动作 攻击颈动脉等要害
Wait, where's its carotid artery?
但它的颈动脉在哪？
Excuse me.
失礼了
Tade!
蓼！
On it!
看我的！
Young Master, it's in your court!
少爷 有劳您了！
Young Master!
少爷！
That was impressive.
那刀真是精彩
Is your armor damaged?
衣服弄脏了吗？
No.
没有
You must be weary.
您想必累了
How about something to eat?
要在这附近用餐吗？
No. Let's press forward.
不用 赶紧出发吧
What are we going to do with the Young Master?
真拿少爷没办法
He's completely besotted with that Northern girl.
完全迷上那位北方女人了
Tade is hungry.
蓼的肚子饿了
Kabru, are you hurt?
喀布尔 你受伤了吗？
Change of plans.
计划有变
It might be tasty stewed with daikon!
这跟萝卜一起炖煮会很好吃吧？
-That's dumb. -Excuse me.
-说什么蠢话 -不好意思
You saved me back there. Thank you.
感谢各位在危急时刻出手相救
I'm Kabru.
我叫喀布尔
May I ask your names?
方便请教尊姓大名吗？
Don't mention it.
别在意
We were just passing through.
刚好路过而已
If I'm not mistaken,
如果我没搞错的话
you're searching for a woman.
你该不会在寻找一位女性吧？
D-Do you know something?
你知道些什么吗？
Just as I thought. My deepest sympathies.
果然啊 我对此深表同情
I might be able to assist you
我说不定能帮上忙
in your search for Falin Touden.
寻找法琳托登小姐
Stop it, Kuro!
小黑 别这样！
Didn't I tell you not to make that expression?
都叫你别摆出那种表情了！
It's frightening!
很恐怖耶！
What's gotten into you?
真是的 你是怎么啦？
And so, Kabru and his crew
就这样 喀布尔等人
decided to venture deeper into the dungeon once again.
再次往迷宫深处前进
NOW
（现在）
Turning back time to Laios and his party,
时间回到现在 当莱欧斯等人
two full days have passed since they agreed to head back.
决议回到地表两天后
It's a dead end.
是死路
Another dead end.
又是死路
I'm famished.
肚子饿了
I'm exhausted.
好困
I'm parched.
口好渴
They were lost and on the brink of death.
正迷路而濒临死亡
Subtitle translation by: Ai Matsuoka
字幕翻译：柯欣冉